whoi.edu 2016-12-05

# Privacy Policy

## Stay informed with our monthly newsletter

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution.

#### Information Collection and Use

Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution collects information from our users at several different points on our Website. 

#### Cookies

No personally identifiable information (e-mail address, name, etc.) is collected with the cookies that we set, and accepting cookies while on the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution site will not put the user at risk for marketing to other sites. 

Different browsers have different cookie-settings. With Netscape you can ask the browser to allow, warn you, or completely disable cookies. Internet Explorer has an additional feature where you can specify different settings for different security zones. You can choose to allow Websites to create cookies for you in your "trusted sites" (like Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution), to warn you before you create them in your local Intranet zone, and to give you an option to never allow them in a "restricted zone." See the "Help" section of your particular browser for more information on working with cookies. 

#### Web Statistics

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use for reporting and sponsorship purposes. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

#### Sharing

We will share aggregated demographic information with our sponsors and donors. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We only share this information so that we can secure funding to continue providing this site free of charge. 

#### Links

This Website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution does not claim any responsibility for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Website. 

#### Security

This Website takes every precaution to protect our users' information, and we have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. 

#### Surveys and Feedback section

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via Web surveys. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include demographic information (such as education level), but no information that can identify any individual person will be collected. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. 

#### Send This to a Friend

If a user elects to use our "Send this to a friend" function, we ask them for the friend's name and e-mail address. Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the site. Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution stores this information temporarily for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. 

#### I'd Like to Know More About

If a user elects to use our "I'd like to know more about" function, we ask them to choose a topic/s that they would like more information about. Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution will send periodic updates regarding the topic/s. The user has the option to unsubscribe at any time. 

#### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this page. 

#### Donor Privacy

The Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution (WHOI) is committed to respecting the privacy of our donors. We have developed this privacy policy to ensure our donors that donor information will not be shared with any third party. 

WHOI provides this Donor Privacy Policy to inform you of the way your information is used. We also provide you with the opportunity to remove your name from (or opt out of) our mailing list, if you desire to do so. 

#### Donor Contact Information

WHOI collects and uses various information from donors that includes: amount donated, address, telephone number, donor comments and e-mail address. Tax laws in the United States require WHOI to keep contact information and contribution level of donors on file. 

WHOI uses donor information to understand donors' needs and provide excellent service. WHOI will never sell, trade, rent or share names (unless released for publication), e-mail or mail addresses, or telephone numbers of our donors. Donors names will be listed in our annual donor report, unless otherwise instructed. This report is distributed only to donors (not the general public). WHOI will use contact information (e-mail, telephone number and address) of donors for these purposes only: 

  * Distribute receipts for donations
  * Thank donors for their donation
  * Inform donors about upcoming fundraising and other activities at WHOI
  * Internal analysis and record keeping
  * Reporting to relevant U.S. and State agencies (these reports are not for public inspection)
  * Contact donors about changes to this policy

Properly anonymized donor information is used for promotional and fundraising activities. WHOI allows donors the option to have their name publicly associated with their donation in an annual donor report unless the donor explicitly chooses to remain "anonymous". 

#### Financial Information

All access to donor financial information is strictly limited to professional staff of WHOI whose job requires them to process this data. No such data is given to any person, organization or group who does not need to access those data. Donor records are kept in secure file cabinets. 

To accept contributions via credit card, WHOI uses accredited online payment processing services with world-class security and data privacy policies. Unless requested by the donor for the purpose of processing recurring donations, WHOI does not store, nor does it have access to, your credit card information, bank account numbers, or other account data sent to those processing services. It is our desire to not send unwanted mail or information about WHOI to our donors. Please contact us if you wish to be removed from our mailing list. 

#### Questions or Comments

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Website, you can contact us using the information below.
